

# Pedro Monteiro

23 years Portuguese

MSc degree in Computer Science Engineering from Aveiro University, where I developed a thesis titled "Real-Time Weapon Detection in Surveillance Video Footage." I am a motivated individual with strong communication skills and a passion for teamwork. Throughout my academic journey, I actively participated in various extracurricular activities and joined several organizations to continuously develop my skills.

#### Contacts



pmapm@ua.pt



/pedromonteiro01



/pedromonteiro01



www.pedromonteiro01.com



Guarda, Portugal

## **Projects**

- Tetris Al Game Python
- Professor Schedule Assigner ReactJS/ FastAPI/MySQL/Docker
- SendASnack React/Spring Boot/ MariaDB/CircleCI/Codacy/Mockito/ Cucumber/JUnit/Jest/Jira
- Gym Website HTML/CSS/JavaScript/ Docker/Spring Boot/MySQL
- Real-Time Weapon Detection in Surveillance Video Footage -React/Django/MySQL/RabbitMQ/Jest/ Selenium/YOLOv5

## Languages

- English B2
- Portuguese Native

#### Education

#### **Aveiro University**

Computer Science Engineering MSc Degree, 2022 - 2024

#### Aveiro University

Computer Science Engineering BSc Degree, 2019 - 2022

### **Experience**

#### Information Systems and Technologies Specialist

Information and Communication Technologies Services - Aveiro University

July 2023 - present

• I work in Agile/Scrum environments, actively participating in the full software development lifecycle. I collaborate proactively with crossfunctional teams to define and design innovative features, aligning technical objectives with business goals. My focus is on developing robust, scalable applications that meet user needs, ensuring our software's effectiveness.

#### Platform Management Team Leader

Informatics Students National Meeting - ENEI January 2023 - October 2023

 Responsible for developing and leading the team in charge of creating the web application that supports Portugal's national meeting of computer science students in Aveiro.

#### Research & Development

Information and Communication Technologies Services - Aveiro July 2022 - July 2023

· After successfully concluding my bachelor's degree final project with a classification of 19/20, I was invited, along with my colleagues, to continue to work with the intent to make it closer to a productionready product, set to be used by the university's community.

#### Internal Management Section Member

Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática AAUAv November 2021 - July 2023

· Responsible for maintaining and creating new features on the course website, working with React, PHP and MySQL.

#### **Business Relations Section Member**

Scientific Junior Value

March 2022 - October 2022

- Development of the new website working with React and GraphQL.
- Event organization and contact with business network.

## **Certificates**

Full Stack Web Development - Udemy September 2021. Python Django - Udemy September 2021.

### Skills

